舰长日志，星历1329.8
Captain's log, stardate 1329.8.
联邦星舰进取号正追踪一艘身份不明的飞船
The USS Enterprise in pursuit of an unidentified vessel.
就在那，长官
There he is, sir.
屏幕中央
Centre screen.
想甩开我们，长官
Still trying to run away from us, sir.
别跟丢了，苏鲁
Don't lose him, Mr. Sulu.
遵命
No, sir.
是我方星舰吗，史波克？
Earth ship, Mr. Spock?
不好说，舰长，我们没有收到它发出的船只登记讯号
Difficult to say, captain. We're getting no registration beam from it.
若是我方星舰，它的引擎就快过载了
If it is, he'll soon overload his engines.
长官，对方引擎严重过载
Sir, he's pushing his engines too hard.
航线也变了
Changing course again.
他知道我们在跟踪他
He knows we're after him, all right.
跟好喽，苏鲁
Stay with him, Mr. Sulu.
- 有回复吗？ - 所有频率都试过了，长官
- Communication? - I've tried all frequencies, sir.
对方拒绝回应
He refuses to answer,
除非他没收到信号
unless he's not receiving us.
没收到就不会溜这么快了
Oh, he's receiving us all right.
前面就是小行星带了，舰长
Approaching an asteroid belt, captain.
希勒等级3-5
Shiller rating 3-5.
开启偏转器，法瑞尔
Deflectors on, Mr. Farrell.
他也看到小行星了，长官
He's seen the asteroid too, sir.
跟好了
Stay with him.
他想利用小行星甩开我们
He'll try to lose us in them.
如果他撞到一颗…
If one of them hits him--
传感器已经显示出那艘船的数据，舰长
Sensor reading on the vessel, captain.
对方是一艘小型J级货船
I make it out as a small class-J cargo ship.
它的引擎已经过热
And his engines are superheating.
警告对方，这样会失去动力…
Try to warn him. If he loses power now--
对方引擎熄火了，长官
There go his engines, sir.
他在小行星带里乱撞，舰长
He's drifting into asteroid belt, captain.
对方已失去动力
He's had it,
只能用我们的偏导护盾罩住他
unless we put our deflector screen around him.
舰长，我们的引擎会因此过载
Captain, if we try, we'll overload our own engines.
距离太远了
He's too far away.
用偏导护盾罩住对方，法瑞尔
Cover him with our deflector screen, Mr. Farrell.
史考特、史波克，去传送室待命
Scotty, Spock, stand by in the Transporter Room.
是，长官
Aye, sir.
对方已在我方保护下，长官
We're protecting him, sir.
但我们撑不了多久
We won't be able to hold him long.
我们超负荷了，舰长，引擎正在升温
We're overloading, captain. Engine temperatures climbing.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages Of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢地航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：kmdangdangli，土豆爱，马田的心事
校对：喜马拉雅，xjCGI
第一季第六集
马德的女人
轮机室报告
This is the Engine Room.
引擎温度已过警戒线
Temperatures are passing the danger line.
偏导护盾正在消退，长官
Our deflector screen's weakening, sir.
我们快撑不住了
We can't protect them much longer.
烧坏一根锂晶体回路，长官
That was one of our lithium-crystal circuits, sir.
舰桥呼叫传送室
Bridge to Transporter Room.
再不把人传送过来的话…
If you don't start beaming that crew over soon--
他们一直都没有回应我们的讯号
They're not answering our signal.
无法锁定救援目标
There's nothing to lock on to.
又烧坏一根，长官
Another circuit, sir.
收到对方求救信号，长官
I'm getting a distress signal call from them, sir.
史考特，收到对方求救信号
Scotty, we're getting a distress signal.
锁定救援目标，舰长
We're locked on to something, captain.
很感激救下我们的命，但能告诉我这是哪儿吗？
Meaning no ingratitude, gentlemen, but just where is it I find meself?
你登上了联邦星舰进取号
You're aboard the USS Enterprise.
噢…这艘星舰真是美极了
Oh, it's really a darn beautiful ship, isn't it?
美极了，这艘星舰
Really a beautiful ship.
先生们，我叫沃尔什，里奥·沃尔什舰长
The name, gentlemen, is Walsh. Captain Leo Walsh.
你还有几名船员？
How many more in your crew?
不多，就几个
Just a few more.
你的船就快不行了，老兄
Your vessel's breaking up, man.
要是再不把人救过来…
If we don't get them over here right now--
我总得先探探你们是敌是友啊
Well, we couldn't be sure you was a friendly vessel, now, could we?
其他三人估计已经各就各位啦
But the three of them will be in position right about by now.
又烧坏一根锂电路
Another lithium circuit.
现在用备用能源提供动力，长官
Now supplementing with battery power, sir.
史考特
Scotty,
救了多少人？
how many of them did you get aboard?
就一人，长官，另外三个已被锁定
Only one, sir. But we've locked on to three more.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
不知道，长官
I don't know, sir.
烧坏三根锂晶体…
With those three lithium crystals gone--
使用电池供能会需要长些时间
At best, it'll take longer on battery.
这玩意儿本来就不靠谱
Never did trust this thing in the first place.
撞上了
There she goes.
小行星撞到船体的要害
Asteroid. Hit him dead centre.
舰桥呼叫传送室
Bridge to Transporter Room.
那艘船被小行星击中了，已经毁灭
Their vessel has been hit by an asteroid. It's gone.
队员是否获救？
Did you get the crew off?
还没，长官，但已锁定救援目标
Not yet, sir, but we've hooked on to something.
寇克呼叫传送室，汇报进展
Kirk to Transporter Room. Report.
别害怕，宝贝们
It's all right, darlings.
他们都是好人
We're in good hands.
舰桥呼叫传送室
Bridge to Transporter Room.
我们已驶出小行星带，舰长
We're clearing the asteroid belt now, captain.
法瑞尔，降下偏导护盾以节省能源
Deflector screen down, Mr. Farrell. Conserve power.
舰长呼叫传送室
Captain to Transporter Room.
听得见我说话吗，史考特？
Are you reading me or not, Mr. Scott?
舰桥呼叫传送室，我们救了多少人？
Bridge to Transporter Room. How many did we get off?
总共四名，长官
Four in all, sir.
若那个船长安然无恙，就让他立即到我房间见我
If the captain of that vessel can walk, I want him in my cabin immediately.
更正
Correction.
他就是瘸了也要立刻来见我，完毕
I want him there whether he can walk or not. Kirk out.
那家伙说话有点冲，不是吗？
That fella sounded a mite upset, didn't he?
正是
Yes.
正，她们很正
Yes, they are.
真稀奇
Curious.
你确定所有人都到齐了吗，沃尔什先生？
You're certain this was everyone aboard, Mr. Walsh?
没人落下？
No other crewmen?
噢…没人啦，都齐啦
Oh, no, that's everyone all right.
但至于我的船员为什么都是些姑娘…
But so far as the ladies actually being the crew--
你可以留待向舰长解释
You can explain that to the captain.
的确是得好好解释，史考特
Amen to that, Scotty.
噢…这里的船员个个都很棒
Oh, sure, these starships are really something marvellous,
但男人终究还是男人，不论在哪
but men will always be men, no matter where they are.
男人的天性与生俱来，你说是吧，先生
Hey, mister, you'll never take that out of them.
12号甲板
Deck 12.
你有瓦肯血统？
You're part Vulcanian, aren't you?
漂亮脸蛋对你毫无吸引
Well then, a pretty face doesn't affect you at all, does it?
除非你动了凡心
That is, not unless you want it to.
省省吧，姑娘们
You can save it, girls.
他这一型的男人根本不食人间烟火
This type can turn himself off from any emotion.
他的话，我很抱歉，长官
I apologise for what he said, sir.
他做惯了买卖人口的…
He's so used to buying and selling people--
这里就让我来处理吧，亲爱的
I'll handle the conversation, darling.
进来
Come.
运输船指挥官求见，舰长
The commander of the transport to see you, captain.
好，你能不能让他…
Good. Now, if you don't mind telling--
你好呀
Hello.
女士们好
Hello, ladies.
她们是你的船员吗，舰长？
Is this your crew, captain?
嗯…不是，舰长
Well, no, captain.
她们是我运送的货物
This is me cargo.
舰长日志，星历1329.1
Captain's log, stardate 1329.1.
我们从一艘来路不明的货船上救出
we have taken aboard from unregistered transport vessel,
一位舰长
its captain
和三位特别的女士
and three unusual females.
她们有股神秘的吸引力
These women have a mysterious magnetic effect
把我所有的男部下都迷住了
on the male members of my crew,
我也不例外
including myself.
目前还无法解释
Explanation unknown at present.
鬼才知道这是艘星舰！
Well, how the devil am I supposed to know this is a starship, captain?
我和那些年轻可爱的“货物”
There I am with a cargo of young lovelies,
碰到艘陌生的飞船…
a strange ship comes up alongside...
情急之下我当然是避而远之喽
Well, naturally I did me best to evade you.
就算是舰长，你也越权啦
And starship captain or no, you exceeded your authority
不该把我们逼到小行星带
when you drove me and mine into a shower of asteroids.
- 姓名？ - 沃尔什，里奥·沃尔什
- Your name, please? - Walsh. Leo Walsh.
你把我的船给毁了，舰长
You destroyed me ship, captain.
沃尔什先生，针对此事，我正召集听证会
Mr. Walsh, I’m convening a ship's hearing on your actions.
史波克先生会为你提供
Mr. Spock will supply you with any
一切有利于你的法律资料
legal information you may need for your defence.
- 你真是不讲情面，舰长 - 而你是个骗子，沃尔什先生
- You're a hard-nosed one, captain. - And you're a liar, Mr. Walsh.
我们都知道对方是什么样的人
I think we both understand each other.
安全人员
Security.
护送沃尔什先生回舱房，不许他出来
Escort Mr. Walsh to his quarters. Confine him there.
该你值班啦，约翰尼
You're on duty, Johnny-O.
回到现实吧
Back to reality.
她们的眼睛真勾魂
You can feel their eyes when they look at you.
整个人像被牢牢抓住
Like something grabbing hold of you.
- 你发现了吗？ - 发现了
- You notice that? - I noticed.
当然发现啦
How I noticed.
冷静冷静，约翰尼，好吗？
Cool it, now, Johnny, okay?
我们遇到麻烦了，史波克
I've got trouble, Mr. Spock.
我知道那是什么，史考特
I'm well aware of that, Mr. Scott.
还剩一块锂晶体，底部还有条极细的裂纹
One lithium crystal left, and that with a hairline split at the base.
那就安个迂回电路
Better rig a bypass circuit.
安不了，整个转换器组件都烧坏了
Can't. We blew the whole converter assembly.
- 我是寇克 - 需要来舰桥一趟，舰长
- Kirk here. - Needed on the bridge, captain.
安静，安静
Calm down, now.
能出去等吗？
Do you mind waiting outside?
- 不能，先生 - 那好吧
- Sorry, sir. - Well.
他们问什么就答什么，别撒谎
Now, answer every question they put to you. Don't lie.
况且也没那个必要，是吧？
Well, you've no need to, have you?
就是别去体检…
And don't submit to a med--
你们这么健康，没必要体检，对吧？
That is, being so healthy, they've no need for a medical exam, have they?
- 他们要是… - 他们不会
- But what if they ask us about--? - They won't.
- 就不能回避一下吗？ - 他们会发现我们不是…
- Have you no place to go, lads? - They'll notice we're dif--
打住，打住，他们不会
No, no, no, they won't.
所有棘手的问题都交给我
You just let Leo take all the hard questions.
好啦，别害怕，宝贝们
Now, don't be panicking, loves.
- 会有出路… - 哪还有出路？
- We'll get to-- - Get where?
飞船没了，航线也不对，哈利
We don't have a ship, and we're headed the wrong way, Harry.
里…
Le--
叫我里奥，里奥·沃尔什是我的名字，亲爱的
Leo. Leo Walsh is me name, darling.
可别忘了
Don't forget that.
真美呀，我们是不是很美呀？
So lovely. Lovely, aren't they?
心地也美，笑得也美
If they'll only think lovely thoughts, if they smile,
我们一定有法子找到出路的，对吧？
why, they'll come out right some which way, now, won't they?
以我所有身家担保
Me personal guarantee on that.
星舰的动力全靠一块锂晶体输送
The entire ship's power is feeding through one lithium crystal.
那就用迂回电路分流
Then switch to bypass circuits.
当引擎过热时它们全被烧毁了，舰长
We burned them all out when we superheated, captain.
沃尔什那个蠢货，不仅没保住自己的船，还为了面子…
That jackass Walsh not only wrecked his own vessel, but in saving his skin--
有件事你听了可能会好受些
If it makes you feel any better, engineer,
那个蠢货的老底就快被揭开了
that's one jackass we're going to see skinned.
但情况还是令人担忧
But it's frustrating.
一百多万吨级的飞船
Almost a million gross tons of vessel
现在就靠拳头大的一块晶体
depending on a hunk of crystal the size of my fist.
那块晶体根本撑不住
And that crystal won't hold up.
输送动力不能光指望它
Not pulling all our power through it.
有何打算，史波克？
Well, Mr. Spock?
在参宿七-12号行星有座锂矿厂
There's a lithium-mining operation on Rigel XII.
- 是高品位矿石，我听说过 - 位置和距离
- High-grade ore, I've heard. - Location and distance.
法瑞尔知道航向
Mr. Farrell has the course.
- 不到两天的航程 - 史波克先生，我们现在就开往参宿七-12
- Less than two days' travel. - Make for Rigel XII, Mr. Spock.
驶向参宿七-12，法瑞尔先生
Rigel XII, Mr. Farrell.
你知道航向
You have the course.
舰长日志，星历1329.2
Captain's log, stardate 1329.2.
在联邦星舰进取号上，正召开一个听证会
Onboard the USS Enterprise, a ship's hearing is being convened
对运输船的船长要进行一场审讯
against the transport vessel's captain.
我愈发担心那几个女人带来的
I'm becoming concerned about the almost hypnotic effect
类似催眠的影响
produced by the women.
听证会开始
This hearing is convened.
星历1329.2，在联邦星舰进取号上
Stardate 1329.2, onboard starship USS Enterprise.
对运输船船长里奥·沃尔什开始正式审讯
Formal hearings against Transport Captain Leo Walsh.
启动电脑
Start computer.
报出你的姓名，以便记录在案
State your name for the record.
里奥·弗朗西斯·沃尔什
Leo Francis Walsh.
不正确
Incorrect.
你的真实姓名
Your correct name.
先生们，你们肯定不会相信一台毫无感情的机器
Gentlemen, surely you're not going to take the word of a soulless
而不去相信一个有血有肉的人吧
mechanical device over that of a real flesh-and-blood man.
报上你的真实姓名，以备记录
State your correct name for the record.
- 哈利·马德 - 不正确
- Harry Mudd. - Incorrect.
哈考特·芬顿·马德
Harcourt Fenton Mudd.
有什么前科，马德先生？
Any past offences, Mr. Mudd?
当然没有，绅士们，我只是一个老实的生意人
Of course not. Gentlemen, I'm simply an honest businessman.
不正确
Incorrect.
真想砸了那个锡皮罐子
Blast that tin-plated pot.
即将显示全部数据
Full data coming on screen.
（警方记录）
如果它也能读出我们的想法…
If it can read our minds too...
不能，可人儿，他们不能
They can't, darling. They can't.
它只知道记录上有的
Just what's on the record.
违法记录：走私
Offence record: smuggling.
判决：缓刑
Sentence: Suspended.
运输赃物
Transport of stolen goods.
用假币购买太空船
Purchase of space vessel with counterfeit currency.
判决：精神疗法，有效性不确定
Sentences: Psychiatric treatment. Effectiveness disputed.
马德先生，您被指控进行无计划星际旅行
Mr. Mudd, you are charged with galaxy travel without a flight plan,
没有身份识别讯号
without an identification beam,
同时拒绝回应星舰讯号
and failure to answer a starship's signal,
因此对星际航行产生了威胁…
thus effecting a menace to navigation--
什么？我那艘很小的飞船在这个浩瀚的银河系
What, my tiny little ship in this immense galaxy?
构成一个航行威胁吗？
A menace to navig--?
你也被控告无照操作飞船
You're also charged with operation of a vessel without a master's licence.
不对，我有船长执照
Untrue. I have a master's ticket.
不正确
Incorrect.
船长执照已于星历1116.4被吊销
Master's licence revoked, stardate 1116.4.
全都对
All right.
哦，很简单
Well, very simply,
里奥·沃尔什，也就是这次旅行中我曾经的船长
Leo Walsh, who was to be my captain on this trip,
突然去世了
passed away suddenly.
我只能接过担子，对吧？
I had no choice but to take out me ship me own self, did I?
我…我就借里奥的名字航行
Well I-- I assumed Leo's name for this voyage, out of...
出于尊敬，为了纪念他，我继续飞行
...courtesy to him. In memoriam, as it were.
好啊，好人啊
Fine, fine man.
唉，就这样去逝了
Alas, gone to his reward.
旅途的目的地和意图？
Destination and purpose of journey?
蛇夫座3号行星，嫁妻移民
Planet Ophiuchus III. Wiving settlers.
再说一遍，马德先生，你要干什么？
Come again, Mr. Mudd? You do what?
我为移民者选妻子
I recruit wives for settlers.
很不容易的一项任务，但一定会让人满意
A difficult but satisfying task.
查找证人数据
Data on witnesses.
无数据
No data.
电脑，转用传感器探测，有何特别的读数吗？
Computer, go to sensor probe. Any unusual readings?
对女士们无可判读数据
No decipherable reading on females.
然而，对男性船员有些特别的读数
However, unusual reading on male board members.
检测到高速呼吸频率
Detecting high respiration patterns,
流汗率增加
perspiration rates up,
心跳急速
heartbeat rapid,
血压高于正常
blood pressure higher than normal.
好了，足够了
Well, that's sufficient.
从记录里删除刚才的信息，史波克先生
Strike that from the record, Mr. Spock.
绅士们，你们看到了吗？就像我说过的一样
Do you see, gentlemen? Just as I told you,
3位可爱的女士就要去往边境行星
three lovely ladies destined for frontier planets
成为孤独男人的伴侣
to be the companions of lonely men.
提供极度匮乏的人性温暖
To supply that warmth of a human touch that's so desperately needed.
妻子、家、家庭
A wife, a home, a family.
先生们，我把这项工作看成神圣的公益事业
Gentlemen, I look upon this work as a sacred public trust.
我毕生都献给了这项事业
I've devoted me whole life to it.
不正确
Incorrect.
哦，我是即将开始贡献我的一生给这项事业
Well, I'm about to start devoting my entire life to it.
这些女士都是自愿来的吗？
Did these ladies come voluntarily?
哦，当然了，比如说
Well, of course. For example,
露丝从海洋行星来到这里，那里是海洋牧场
Ruthie here comes from a pelagic planet. Sea ranches.
玛格达，来自氦元素实验站
Magda, there, from the Halium experimental station.
我们的情况都一样，舰长，没有男人
It's the same story for all of us, captain. No men.
我的是一个农场行星
Mine was a farm planet
和自动机器为伍
with automated machines for company,
我要为两个哥哥做饭，给他们缝补衣服
and two brothers to cook for, mend their clothes,
每次他们走进屋子时靴子上都带了一脚泥巴
canal mud a foot thick on their boots every time they walked in.
- 好了，伊芙，好了 - 不，还没完呢
- Fine, Evie, fine. - No, it's not fine.
有很多男人都等着做我们的丈夫
We've got men willing to be our husbands waiting for us
你们现在正把我们带去相反的方向
and you're taking us in the opposite direction.
盯着我们看，就好像我们是来自土星的后宫宠物
Staring at us like we were Saturnius harem girls or something.
够了，伊芙
That's enough, Evie.
对马德先生的唯一指控
The only charges are against Mr. Mudd,
非法运营一艘飞船
illegal operation of a vessel.
你有什么要辩护的吗？
Do you have any defence to offer?
只有上天知道真相
Only heaven's own truth,
我说的都是真的
which I've just given you.
听证会结束
The hearing is closed.
我们一有机会，就要把马德先生
Mr. Mudd to be handed over to the legal authorities
交给司法部门处理
at our earliest opportunity.
那我们呢？我们会怎样？
And what about us? What happens to us?
帮帮我们，求您了，帮帮我们几个
Help us, please, all of us.
麦克赫龙小姐，如果你不介意…
Miss McHuron, if you don't mind--
长官，最后的晶体烧毁了
The last crystal, sir. It's gone.
寇克舰长，轮机部门报告，全体生命支持系统
Captain Kirk, Engineering section reports our entire life-support system
现在全靠电池供能
is now on batteries.
- 史波克先生   - 麦克赫龙小姐，请让一下 - 不，求您了
- Mr. Spock-- Miss McHuron, please. - No, please.
史波克先生，请联络一下参宿七-12号上的矿工好吗？
Would you mind? Mr. Spock, will you contact the miners on Rigel XII?
通知他们我们一到就要拿到锂晶体
Notify them that we'll need the lithium crystals immediately upon arrival.
哦，你这美丽的银河系啊
Oh, you beautiful galaxy.
哦，那神圣的宇宙啊
Oh, that heavenly universe.
怎么了，姑娘们，那些是锂矿工人
Why, girls, lithium miners.
你们不明白么？
Don't you understand?
孤单寂寞的、劳苦功高的、财大气粗的锂矿工人啊
Lonely, isolated, overworked, rich lithium miners.
姑娘们，你们还想要丈夫吗？
Girls, do you still want husbands?
伊芙，你不必只为了一个船长在一棵树上吊死
Evie, you won't have to be satisfied with a mere ship's captain.
我会给你找一个能买下整个行星的男人
I'll get you a man who can buy you a whole planet.
玛吉，你就要成为伯爵夫人了
Maggie, you're going to be a countess.
露丝，我要让你成为公爵夫人
Ruth, I'll make you a duchess.
而我呢…
And I...
我要接管这艘星舰
I'll be running this starship.
詹姆士·寇克舰长
Captain James Kirk,
以后的命令就要由哈考特·芬顿·马德来下达了
the next orders you're taking will be given by Harcourt Fenton Mudd.
舰长日志，星历1330.1
Captain's log, stardate 1330.1.
我们现在距参宿七-12还有14个小时航程
Position, 14 hours out of Rigel XII.
现在我们正使用辅助脉冲引擎
we're on auxiliary impulse engines.
燃料不多，到达行星轨道的燃料勉强够用
Fuel low, barely sufficient to achieve orbit over the planet.
更换锂晶体势在必行
Lithium replacements are now imperative.
马德的女人们对我舰成员的影响逐渐增加
The effect of Mudd's women on my crew continues to grow,
但原因仍旧不明
still totally unexplained.
哈利·马德在看守下被软禁
Harry Mudd is confined to his quarters under guard.
我可以进来吗？
May I come in?
有事吗，可以啊，请进，当然可以
Why, yes. Please do, by all means.
康诺斯，你完事了吗？
Connors, are you finished?
我一直想知道这个地方是什么样子
I was wondering what this place looked like.
真令人神魂颠倒
It's fascinating.
请…？
Would--?
请你再走过我的显示面板，好吗？
Would you walk past my panel again, please?
你的什么？
Your what?
我的医疗扫描仪
My medical scanner.
哦，怎么了？你不是要给我体检吧？
Oh, why? You're not giving me an examination, are you?
哦，不是，我只是不能相信…
Oh, no, I wouldn't trust my--
我的判断，相信我，只要靠一下就可以
My judgement. Believe me. Just walk by, please.
不应该的啊
It's not supposed to do that.
我想知道，你会给参宿七-12上的矿工体检吗？
I wondered, will you be examining the miners on Rigel XII?
会的，如果他们需要的话
Yes, if they need it.
你是说还没问过吧？
You mean you haven't asked yet?
他们真的身体健康吗？
Are they in good health and all that?
什么？
What?
哦，是的
Oh, yes.
他们相当健康
They're in excellent health.
全部三人都很健康
All three of them.
哦，三个人
Oh, three.
你是不是用了哪种特别的香水？
Are you wearing some unusual kind of perfume,
或者是放射性的物质，亲爱的？
or something radioactive, my dear?
没有啊，我就是我
No. I'm just me.
真奇怪那到底是什么引起的
I wonder what makes it do that.
舰长
Captain.
希望你不会介意
I hope you don't mind.
实际上，麦克赫龙小姐，我介意
As a matter of fact, Ms. McHuron, I do.
哦，我试着到处走走，我只是…
Well, I was trying to take a walk, and I just--
我就闯进了这里，你看…
I just had to run in someplace. You see--
我想说的是，你的人全盯着我看
I mean, all your men were looking at me,
他们的眼神都跟随着我
following me with their eyes.
是啊，看来我得和他们谈谈了
Yes. I'll have to talk to them about that.
他们…
They...
…平时不是那样的，麦克赫龙小姐
...don't do that ordinarily, Ms. McHuron.
但是这次，遇到了你们几位，情况就…
But somehow in your case, and the ladies with you, it's--
哦，他们可能太孤单了
Well, they're probably just lonely.
我能理解孤单的感觉
I can understand loneliness.
是啊
Yes.
是啊，现在，麦克赫龙小姐，如果你不介意，我…
Yes. Now, Miss McHuron, if you don't mind, I--
我…我认为
I-- I suppose
我认为你的体会更深
I suppose you understand it even more.
我意思是，要管理这么大一艘星舰
I mean, having to run a huge ship like this
每分每秒都肩负重任
with so much responsibility every minute
与那些仰慕你的船员相处必须要仔细周到…
and having to be so careful with all your men looking up to you...
噢，比那可能还要更难
Well, it probably appears more difficult than it is.
我知道，一个舰长必须要做的十全十美
I read once, a commander has to act like a paragon of virtue.
我从没遇见过十全十美的人
I never met a paragon.
我也没见过
Neither have I.
噢，当然没见过，没有人是十全十美的
Well, of course not. No one is.
但有的人得努力扮演
But some people try to pretend.
你要努力吗，舰长？
Do you, captain?
麦克赫龙小姐，我…我不…
Ms. McHuron, I-- I don't--
哦，不
Oh, no.
哦，我做不来，我才不管哈利·马德说了什么
Oh, I just can't do it. I don't care what Harry Mudd says.
我真的是喜欢你
I do like you,
我就是不能按他说的那样做
and I just can't go through with it.
我讨厌这种事！
I hate this whole thing!
就三个人，你确定吗？
Just three, you're sure?
- 是的，矿工们身体健康而且相当年轻 - 等一下，亲爱的
Yes, the miners are healthy and fairly young. Later, dear.
玛格达，你打听到什么底细了吗？
Magda, did you get to your communications man?
矿工头儿叫本·柴德里斯
The head miner is named Ben Childress.
另外两个叫格赛特和本顿
The others are Gossett and Benton.
- 而且他们已经到那里… - 快3年了
- And they've been there-- - Almost three years now.
没有家人
Alone.
太棒了
Perfect.
一共三个人，哈利·马德刚好有三位可爱的女士
Three of them, and three lovely ladies has Harry Mudd.
亲爱的，锂晶体的价值
And lithium crystals, my dear, are worth
比等质量的钻石高出300倍
300 times their weight in diamonds.
比等质量的黄金高出几千倍
Thousands of times their weight in gold.
但是他们在下面
But they'll be down there, and we'll be up here
我们却在他们头顶上几百里的地方绕圈子
circling a hundred miles above them.
而且你的门外还有守卫，哈利
And there's a guard outside your door, Harry.
你连舱门都出不了
You can't get out of your cabin.
恰好相反，亲爱的
No, my dears.
你们只要再稍稍费些劲儿，被困可就不是我了
After one more little job for you, it won't be Harry Mudd that's trapped.
而是一位先生，詹姆士…
It'll be a gentleman named James T--
我讨厌你
I don't like you.
我也讨厌我自己
And I’m not very happy with myself either.
对此我并不惊讶
Well, I’m not really surprised.
我知道你对舰长有意思
I've seen you noticing the captain.
我们本来就该对他们有意思
We're supposed to notice them!
哈利，我…
Oh, Harry, I--
我有些不舒服
I don't feel very good.
一定是期限快到了
I think it must be near the time.
我说过进入预轨道航线，法瑞尔先生
I asked for a preorbital course, Mr. Farrell.
长官，已进入预轨道航线
Pre-orbital course locked in, sir.
先生们，同样的命令我不会再说两遍了
That's the last time I'm giving an order twice, gentlemen.
现在电池的能量也所剩无几
We're down to battery power, and we're low on that.
足以撑到参宿七-12号，长官，但轨道不太稳定
They'll get us to Rigel XII, sir, but it'll be a shaky orbit.
史考特，留在轨道上直到拿到6个锂晶体为止
Just hang us in there long enough to get six crystals, Scotty.
- 我们就要这些 - 我把你们送过去
- That's all we need. - I'll get you there.
真是扯淡
Ridiculous.
以为我们开的是什么？
What are we running here?
你给她们体检了没？
Did you examine them?
你给伊芙做检查了吗？
Did you examine Eve?
她不同意
She refused.
拜托，你可是医生
Well, come on, you're the doctor.
到底是怎么回事？
What is it?
是我们累惨了，还是她们美呆了
Is it that we're tired, and they're beautiful?
她们美的惊为天人
And they are incredibly beautiful.
是吗，吉姆？从各方面来看
Are they, Jim? Are they actually more lovely, pound for pound,
她们真的比你见过的其他女人美吗？
measurement for measurement, than any other women you've known?
会不会她们只是…
Or is it that they just...
装的很美？
...well, act beautiful?
不，这么说不对
No, strike that. Strike that.
老骨头，她们是何方神圣？
What are they, Bones?
你是指她们也许是外星人的幻像之类的吗？
You mean, are they alien illusions, that sort of thing?
我先问你的
I asked you first.
不
No.
这么聪明的外星人应能屏蔽
An alien smart enough to pull this would be smart enough to keep
我的医疗扫描仪
my medical scanner from going:
我听不懂你的话
I don't follow you.
我自己也不懂
I don't either.
优先空间频段3-9
Top-space frequency of 3-9.
呼叫参宿七-12号
Rigel XII. Rigel XII.
这里是参宿七-12，进取号请讲
This is Rigel XII. Come in, Enterprise.
这里不算是进取号
Well, this isn't exactly the Enterprise.
我是哈利·马德
My name is Harry Mudd.
请问阁下是哪位？
To whom have I the pleasure of speaking, sir?
舰长，能量曲线仍在走低
Power curve still dropping, captain.
长官，我们马上进入轨道
We'll make orbit, sir.
- 临时轨道 - 开始
- A temporary one. - Lay in.
电脑
Computer.
轨道能保持3天7小时
We can sustain this orbit for three days, seven hours.
时间充沛
More than enough time.
通讯官，通知参宿七12号委派一名矿工代表
Communications, have a representative of the Rigel XII miners
到舰上来和我们商谈需求事宜
meet us here to discuss our need.
- 先把他传送到营房 - 遵命，长官
- Beam him up first pass over the camp. - Yes, sir.
出什么事了？
What's happening?
看我的脸
Look at my face.
给我们药
Give us the pills.
我们这个样子被人见了怎么办？
What if someone sees us like this?
哈利，你不可能找着药的
You'll never find them, Harry.
如果你真找到了…
And if you do find them...
你明白那是什么吗？
...you know what they are?
骗局一场
A cheat.
如果你在意某人，真的在意…
If you care for someone, really care...
在意谁？寇克？
For whom, Evie? For Kirk?
女士们，舰长们早已和他们的星舰成婚了
You'll find out that ship's captains are already married, girl. To their vessels.
在你们仨首次碰面时你就知道了
You'd find that out the first time you came between him and the ship.
你会明白的
You'll see.
我慢慢变回原来的样子了
I'm going back to what I was.
- 丑陋不堪 - 我受不了自己这个鬼样子
- Ugly. - I can't stand myself like this.
哈利，你为什么把药藏起来？
Why did you hide them, Harry?
- 你不信我们吗？ - 小姐，我没藏
- Don't you trust us? - I didn't hide them, girl.
以防搜身我把药放在安全的地方了
I put them in a safe place in case I was searched.
哈利，找出那些药
Find the pill, Harry.
床垫
Mattress.
找到了
Yes, here.
吃吧，伊芙，吃吧
Go on, Eve, take it.
这不是骗局
It's not a cheat.
这是奇迹
It's a miracle.
有些男人欣赏它
For some man who can appreciate it...
有些男人需要它
...and who needs it.
即便千疮百孔，它们美丽依旧
Even burned and cracked, they're beautiful.
毁掉真是可惜
Destroying them was a shame.
一点也不，史波克
Not at all, Mr. Spock.
在烧毁锂晶体与摧毁他人舰船之间
The choice was burning this lithium crystal or the destruction
只能择其一
of another man's ship.
请进
Come.
长官，采矿主管柴德里斯和格赛特先生已到
Sir, Mining Chief Childress and Mr. Gossett.
好，带他们进来
Good. Show them in.
我是进取号舰长詹姆士·寇克
I'm James Kirk, captain of the Enterprise.
这是我的科学官史波克先生
This is my science officer, Mr. Spock.
让我们开门见山吧
Let's get right to business.
你想要我们拥有的锂晶体
You want lithium crystals, and we've got them.
好吧，我被授权支付一个合理的价钱
Fine. I’m authorized to pay an equitable price.
舰长，钱可买不到这东西
We're not sure they're for sale, captain.
我们做个交换如何
We might prefer a swap.
你们想要什么？
What did you have in mind?
马德手里的女人
Mudd's women.
如果我们要女人，得先看看货
If we like them. We'd like to have a look at them first, of course.
正是
Right.
带她们出来瞧瞧，舰长，还有哈利·马德
Trot them out, captain. Oh, and Harry Mudd.
总之我已同意释放他了，同时撤销对他的指控
Either way, I've agreed to have him released, charges dropped.
诸位还有别的要求吗？
Is there anything else?
寇克，你没得选
You've got no choice, Kirk.
你要是强行派人下去找，必定一无所获
You beam a landing party down, and you won't find one blessed crystal.
没门儿
No deal.
先生们，你们身处太空深处
You're a long way out in space, gentlemen.
你们需要医疗援助，货物运输以及星舰保护
You'll need medical help, cargo runs, starship protection.
这些你们考虑了吗？
You wanna consider those facts too?
女士们，过来
Come along, ladies. Come along.
你一定是本·柴德里斯，快来，小姐们，过来
You must be Ben Childress. Come on now, girls. Come on.
你一定是赫姆·格赛特
And you must be Herm Gossett.
我想我是
Yes, I reckon I am.
马德，我得承认，你说话算话
One thing I'll say for you, Mudd, you're not a liar.
女士们，欢迎欢迎
And ladies, you are welcome.
我还是不同意
It's still no deal.
长官，电池储备的能量只剩一半了
Conserving batteries, sir. Half power.
据我所知3天后轨道会消失，那时你们死定了
I'm told they have only three days of orbit left before they start spiralling in.
舰长，我实在不愿见你遭难，但事实就是事实
I do hate to see you suffering such a situation, captain, but truth is truth,
可悲的是，你会同意这笔交易
and the sad fact is, you will deal.
迟早你得低头
Sooner or later, you'll have to.
舰长日志
Captain's log.
一干人等被传送至参宿七-12行星表面
Transporting down to surface of planet Rigel XII
以便取得替代用的锂晶体
to acquire replacement lithium crystals.
估计会受到矿工们的进一步刁难
Expect further difficulty from miners.
好吧，柴德里斯，你赢了
All right, Childress, you've won.
我要锂晶体
Now I'll take the lithium crystals.
寇克，等我有空了再说
When I have the time, Kirk.
柴德里斯
Childress.
寇克先生，我们正在忙
We're busy, Mr. Kirk.
舰长，没时间等了
We don't have the time to spare, captain.
你有更好的点子？
You got a better idea?
风一直这么吹
Blows like that all the time.
离门几步就会迷路
You can get lost a dozen feet from your own doorstep.
风说来就来
The wind comes up suddenly.
磁暴
Magnetic storm.
这说明马上就狂风大作了
That means the wind'll really rip soon.
和我跳舞吧
Dance with me.
- 想跳舞吗？ - 不…
- Would you like to dance? - No...
抱歉，我…可能是灰尘的原因
I'm sorry, I-- I guess it must be the dust.
参宿七上就这样
That's the way it is on Rigel...
一直都是
...all the time.
- 嘿 - 走开
- Hey. - Go away.
我来抢舞伴
I'm cutting in.
她是我的
Not on me.
你怎么回事？
What's the matter with you?
你为什么不弄个赌局，好让我跟输家走
Why don't you just run a raffle, and the loser gets me.
你们不能出去，会死的
You can't go out there, you'll get killed!
我回来的时候请把锂晶体准备好
Just have those crystals here when I get back.
伊芙
Eve!
舰长日志
Captain's log.
我们已回到进取号，改用红外扫描器
Have transported aboard the Enterprise to implement search
和传感器进行搜救
with infrared scanners and sensing systems.
星球表面的磁暴降低了
Magnetic storms on the planet's surface are cutting down speed
设备的搜救速度和效力
and efficiency of our equipment.
搜救现已持续了3小时18分钟
Search now in progress for three hours, 18 minutes.
横贯纬线3和4
Traverse parallel three and four.
正在检查
Checking...
没什么收获
...but not getting much.
舰长，磁暴正在电离大气层
The storm is ionizing the atmosphere, captain.
透过大气层进行探测困难重重
Getting difficult to probe through it.
舰长，这进一步地消耗了电池的能量
Captain, this is draining our batteries further.
- 要是有锂晶体就好了 - 但是我们没有
- If we only had those crystals. - But we don't!
我什么也没拿到，我应该能拿到的
I didn't get any. I should have found a way.
这样你满意了，史考特先生？
Satisfied, Mr. Scott?
长官，与矿工们失去了联系
Losing communications with the miners, sir.
磁暴似乎更强了
Magnetic storm seems worse.
柴德里斯还没消息吗？
Has Childress reported in yet?
不，长官，还没找到他和那个女孩
No, sir. He and the girl are still missing.
抱歉，史考特
Sorry, Scotty.
- 还剩多少能量？ - 还能坚持5小时，长官
- How much power do we have left? - About five hours, sir.
舰长日志
Captain's log.
43分钟后能量便消耗殆尽
I've expended all but 43 minutes of power.
舰船状况危急
Ship's condition, critical.
搜救现已持续了7小时31分钟
Search now in progress seven hours, 31 minutes.
磁暴正在减弱
Magnetic storms are easing.
红外线读数
Infrared reading.
检查纬线3，栅格0-4-0
Check traverse three, grid 0-4-0.
距采矿公司11里处，方位1-2-1
About 11 miles, bearing 1-2-1 from the mining company.
- 那是本·柴德里斯的舱房 - 房内有加热装置运行
- That's Ben Childress' quarters. - There's a heat unit operating there.
- 也许是个炉子 - 让马德去传送室…
- It could be a cook stove. - Have Mudd meet me
- 与我会合 - 马德？
- in the Transporter Room. - Mudd?
罪魁祸首
The name of this game.
我喜欢房子原来的摆设
I had things where I wanted them.
我吃了些你的食物，所以做了些家务做补偿
I ate some of your food, so I paid with some chores.
我要吃会自己做
And I do my own cooking.
该死
Damn!
记清楚，我可没碰你
Now, I’ve not laid a hand on you. Remember that.
男人的自尊，你穿越了半个银河系
The sound of male ego. You travel halfway across the galaxy,
却本性难移
and it's still the same song.
你的饭
There.
你是吃饭还是接着嚷嚷？
You gonna eat or talk?
我猜我应该坐下，翻翻眼珠
I guess I'm supposed to sit, taste it, roll my eyes, and,
然后说“终于吃到女人做的饭了”
"Oh, female cooking again."
还有比这更好吃的，我自己做的
I've tasted better, by my own hand.
这里面的确有你的贡献
Well, you're tasting some of it now.
锅底全是你烧糊的饭菜，刷都刷不下来
I couldn't scrape three layers of your leavings out of that pan.
有本事找口井用水洗干净，再来抱怨
You find me a well, some decent water, then talk.
你可以把锅挂在外面，风这么大
Well, why don't you hang your pan out in the wind
沙子自然会把它刮干净
and let the sand blast it clean?
别告诉我你压根就没想到
Or hadn't you thought about that?
估计管用
It might work.
- 在玩什么？ - 双J纸牌
- This solitaire? - Double jack.
红桃八得跟黑桃九
The red eight ought to go on the black nine.
双J不这么玩
Not in double jack.
你相貌平平，还不解风情
You're not only plain as an old bucket, you're not even good company.
你那张脸到底怎么了？
What the devil happened to your looks anyway?
和你呆腻了，我缩水了
I got tired of you. I slumped.
这到底怎么回事？
You hear what I said?
你怎么变丑了？
You're homely!
我拥有的水晶够买成千上万个美人！
I've got enough in crystals already to buy queens by the gross!
我可没碰她
I didn't touch her.
谢天谢地你把她找到了
Thank heaven you found her.
她对我的救命之恩念念不忘
She's been bubbling with gratitude ever since.
坐
Sit down.
告诉他
Tell him.
告诉他，哈利
Tell him, Harry.
好吧，呃…
Yes, well...
维纳斯药丸，哈利
The Venus drugs, Harry.
维纳斯药丸？
Venus drug?
听是听说过，但…
I've heard of it, but...
难道真有此药？
It's not just one of those stories?
噢…的确有这种药…
Oh, it exists...
是违法的
...illegally.
呃…实际上这种药没多少副作用
Well, actually, you see, it's a relatively harmless drug.
没有？
Harmless?
是啊…
Yeah...
这种药，能提升你的魅力
Well, what it does is give you more of whatever you have.
男的吃了更健硕，女的嘛…
Well, with men, it makes them more muscular. Women...
更风韵
...rounder.
男的更勇猛女的更温柔…
Men, more aggressive. Women, more feminine and--
来这儿之前，他让她们吃了药
He gave it to the women before you met them.
难道那几个女的也…？
Does that mean the others...?
和她一样又老又丑？
They really look like she does?
- 柴德里斯先生，我… - 是不是这样？
- Mr. Childress, I-- - Is that what it means?
是的，就是这样
Yes, that's what it means.
我的同伴呢？
What happened to my partners?
起风暴的时候他们就各自回屋了，柴德里斯
They've left for their quarters during the storm, Childress.
他们举办了婚礼
They're married.
子空间广播婚礼
Subspace radio marriage.
我们被骗了
It was a fraud.
- 婚礼可以作废 - 只要他们愿意
- They can get out of it. - If they want to.
为什么？
Why?
- 你不能怪这些女人 - 我能
- You can't condemn the women. - I can.
我们这些男人在外面拼死拼活…
A man goes out and fights...
冒着生命危险
...almost dies.
把命都赌上
We all almost died.
活下来只是命大
We should have, but we didn't.
现在生活有了希望
And now that we've got the good life in our hands,
- 你却让我们娶这种女人… - 你要的不是妻子
- you bring us women for wives that-- - You don't want wives.
你要的是它
You want this.
它才是你想要的，柴德里斯先生
This is what you want, Mr. Childress.
你就做你的春秋大梦吧，你没法得到它
I hope you remember it and dream about it, because you can't have it.
它不是真的！
It's not real!
你是要这样的妻子吗，本？
Is this the kind of wife you want, Ben?
不是那个能帮你
Not someone to help you.
能为你缝衣做饭
Not a wife to cook and sew...
会哭泣，要依靠的妻子
...and cry and need.
而是这样一个
This kind.
自私
Selfish,
虚荣
vain,
什么都不会做的妻子
useless.
这真是你想要的？
Is this what you really want?
那好吧…
All right, then...
你的愿望实现了
...here it is.
真是好女人，对吧，柴德里斯？
Quite a woman, eh, Childress?
一个冒牌货
A fake.
靠药丸变美
Pumped up by a drug.
靠她自己
By herself.
她没吃药
She took no drug.
可我把药都吞了
I swallowed it.
只是染色明胶
Coloured gelatine.
的确如此，药被没收了，那是颗假的
Yes, they took away my drug and substituted that.
这怎么可能？
But that can't be.
这种药只对一种女人
There's only one kind of woman.
或男人真正有效
Or man, for that matter.
要么自信满满…
You either believe in yourself...
要么根本不相信自己
...or you don't.
好啦，柴德里斯我没功夫再和你耗下去
All right, Childress, I've gone as far with you as I intend to.
我要那些锂晶体，现在就要
I want those lithium crystals, and I want them now.
进取号，我是寇克
Enterprise, this is Kirk.
- 我是史波克，舰长 - 待命
- Spock here, captain. - Stand by.
需要派搜索队下来吗？
Do I beam down a search party?
不需要
No.
那些…
The...
晶体就在这儿…
The crystals are here...
随时可以拿走
...and you're welcome to them.
待命，史波克
Stand by, Mr. Spock.
锂晶体会随我们一同登舰
We're coming aboard with the lithium crystals.
登舰人数，舰长？
How many coming, captain?
伊芙得留下
Eve will stay.
至少今天留下，我们…
The day at least. We...
我们有话要讲
We wanna talk.
伊芙？
Eve?
你那位还在天上等你呢，她叫进取号
You've got someone up there called the Enterprise.
两名，史波克
Two of us, Mr. Spock.
走吧，马德先生
Come on, Mr. Mudd.
就把我留这儿吧
Don't you think you could possibly, by accident,
就当是你不小心
arrange to leave me behind here?
把我落下，这种惩罚够狠了吧？
On this planet, that would be punishment enough.
那可不行，哈利
I can't do that, Harry.
但我会以目击证人的身份为你当庭作证
But I will appear as a character witness at your trial...
如果那样能帮到你
...if you think that'll help.
那我就等着蹲大牢吧
They'll throw away the key.
你在下面说的那一席话一定感人肺腑
That must have been quite a talk you made down there.
要不要再考虑申请医学专利？
Ever try considering the patent medicine business?
干嘛要我加入你那行？
Why should I work your side of the street?
我很高兴能化险为夷
I'm happy the affair is over.
真是一波三折，惊心动魄
A most annoying, emotional episode.
像一拳打在老心脏的右边
Smack right in the old heart.
哦…抱歉
Oh, I’m sorry.
你的心应该在这儿
In your case, it would be about here.
医生，我这种和你们不同的身体构造
The fact that my internal arrangement differs from yours, doctor,
真令我庆幸不已
pleases me no end.
航线测绘完毕，所有系统运行正常
Course plotted, and all systems in operation.
引擎已经启动，船舵回应正常
Engines engaged. Helm answering.
驶离行星轨道，长官
Out of orbit, sir.
全速前进
Ahead full.
全速前进，长官
Ahead full, sir.
本集结束
-=The Last Fantasy=-
谢谢观赏